
const driverQuestions = [

    {
      question: "While driving you hear a siren sounding behind your vehicle, you should...",
      options: ["Drive faster", "Pull over and stop", "Stop", "Step out of the vehicle"],
      correctAnswer: "Pull over and stop",
      category: "Driving in special situations",
    },
  
    {
      question: "When driving you come across a box junction, and your exit is blocked. The best thing to do is...",
      options: ["Proceed when the filter light is green",
               "Enter the box junction but turn only when your light is green",
                "Enter the box junction if your light is green and exit is clear but traffic is obstructing",
                 "Enter the box junction if there is a guiding vehicle in front of you doing the same"],
      correctAnswer: "Enter the box junction if your light is green and exit is clear but traffic is obstructing",
      category: "Driving in special situations",
    },
  
    {
      question: "What should you do if your vehicle breaks down in the middle of the road?",
      options: ["Turn on your hazard lights, and bring the vehicle to safety before seeking help",
               "Immediately call for mechanic or highway patrol support",
                "Both A and B",
                "None of the above"],
      correctAnswer: "Only A",
      category: "Road Safety",
    },
  
    {
      question: "If a road is blocked and a policeman on point duty stops you and asks you to produce your documents, you should",
      options: ["Reason your case as you did nothing wrong",
               "Show the electronic copy of your vehicle documents",
                "Hand the documents and allow for vehicle inspection",
                "None of the above. Keep driving"],
      correctAnswer: "Hand the documents and allow for vehicle inspection",
      category: "Road Safety",
    },
  
    {
      question: "You are driving up or down a hill with sharp bends and the road ahead is blocked by tree branches.",
      options: ["Honk to let other vehicles be aware of your presence and prepare",
               "Shine your head lights",
                "Drive as you would",
                "Lower your radio volume to prevent distractions"],
      correctAnswer: "Honk to let other vehicles be aware of your presence and prepare",
      category: "Driving in special situations",
    },
  
    {
      question: "What is a garrison in road theory?",
      options: ["A particularly narrow road or bridge",
               "A particularly private property where you must not drive",
                "A particularly dangerous area, known for crime and violence",
                "A gap or area where the road is not safe to drive"],
      correctAnswer: "A particularly dangerous area, known for crime and violence",
      category: "Road Safety",
    },
  
    {
      question: "The safest way to drive on a steep downward hill is in which gear?",
      options: ["Reverse",
               "Reverse or Low",
                "Drive",
                "Neutral"],
      correctAnswer: "Reverse or Low",
      category: "Road Safety",
    },
  
    {
      question: "The security instructs you to drive into another spot even though one nearby is empty.",
      options: ["Park in the empty spot nearby",
               "Park in the spot instructed by the security",
                "Park in front of the gates where it is easy to enter or exit",
                "Park in the spot for cyclists or persons with special needs"],
      correctAnswer: "Park in the spot instructed by the security",
      category: "Parking",
    },
  
    {
      question: "If you have to park in the sun normally, which accessory is best for your vehicle?",
      options: ["Windshield and dashboard protector",
               "Anti-fog mirrors",
                "Spoilers",
                "A car wrap to cover the entire vehicle"],
      correctAnswer: "Windshield and dashboard protector",
      category: "Parking",
    },
  
    {
      question: "If driving in the rain makes you lose control of your steering",
      options: ["Steer sharply towards the soft shoulder or service lane",
               "Ride the brakes gently and slowly with light foot pumps",
                "Release foot of the gas pedal and turn on your hazard lights",
                "Both B and C"],
      correctAnswer: "Both B and C",
      category: "Driving in special situations",
    },
    
    {
      question: "Which of the following are the steps to parallel parking?",
      options: ["Align your rear bumper with the vehicle beside you, turn your steering full and reverse, straighten the wheel and reverse, turn fully to the opposite direction and align",
               "Align your rear bumper with the vehicle beside you, straighten the wheel and reverse, turn your steering full and reverse, turn fully to the opposite direction and align",
                "Align your rear bumper with the vehicle beside you, turn fully to the opposite direction and align, straighten the wheel and reverse, turn your steering full and reverse",
                "None of the above"],
      correctAnswer: "Align your rear bumper with the vehicle beside you, turn your steering full and reverse, straighten the wheel and reverse, turn fully to the opposite direction and align",
      category: "Parking",
    },
  
    {
      question: "It is correct to signal a pedestrian to cross the road when you stop?",
      options: ["Yes",
               "No unless the pedestrian uses the zebra crossing only",
                "No as you must check your mirrors for a car overtaking that may hit the pedestrian",
                "No as you must only give way at a pedestrian light"],
      correctAnswer: "Signal and adjust speed, apply brakes, switch to Park, apply hand brake",
      category: "Learning to Drive",
    },
  
    {
      question: "Why are hand signals important in addition to mechanical signals?",
      options: ["To make your intentions clear",
               "Your mechanical signals may not work or take time to show",
                "To demand right of passage",
                "To instruct drivers how to drive"],
      correctAnswer: "To make your intentions clear",
      category: "Learning to drive",
    },
  
    {
      question: "A good driver will",
      options: ["check mirrors only when they're foggy or dirty",
               "disobey policemen",
                "Never overtake at a corner or bend",
                "drive beyond the speed limit indicated by road signs"],
      correctAnswer: "Never overtake at a corner or bend",
      category: "Driving Morals",
    },
  
    {
      question: "The road shows a road works sign but you see a passable area ahead.",
      options: ["Proceed through the passage but be cautious",
               "Ask for assistance",
                "Drive around as the sign indicates",
                "Make a U turn and drive in the opposite direction"],
      correctAnswer: "Drive around as the sign indicates",
      category: "Road safety",
    },
  
    {
      question: "What is considered safe following distance?",
      options: ["There is no following distance",
               "About two cars length",
                "You should see the entire rear bumper, licence plate and portion of the road",
                "You should see the rear of the car, but not necessarily the road"],
      correctAnswer: "You should see the entire rear bumper, licence plate and portion of the road",
      category: "Learning to drive",
    },
  
    {
      question: "What is a concealed entrance?",
      options: ["Dead end road",
               "Road works in progress",
                "Portion of the road hidden",
                "Crash hotspot"],
      correctAnswer: "Portion of the road hidden",
      category: "Learning to Drive",
    },
  
    {
      question: "A slip road is used to?",
      options: ["Change roads safely without obstructing traffic",
               "Take emergency exits only",
                "Take shortcuts around the intersection",
                "Stop police vehicles from chasing you"],
      correctAnswer: "Change roads safely without obstructing traffic",
      category: "Road safety",
    },
  
    {
      question: "What is defensive driving best made up of?",
      options: ["Observing, Ignoring, Proceeding",
               "Planning, Observing, Anticipating, Honking",
                "Planning, Observing, Waiting, Executing",
                "Planning, Observing, Anticipating, Staying in control"],
      correctAnswer: "Planning, Observing, Anticipating, Staying in control",
      category: "Learning to Drive",
    },
  
    {
      question: "Where should you position your vehicle to turn right?",
      options: ["By the center line or just left of the centre",
               "On the right side of the lane",
                "In between the left and right lane",
                "To the right of the center line"],
      correctAnswer: "By the center line or just left of the centre",
      category: "Learning to Drive",
    },
  
  ];
  
export default driverQuestions;